# **DANIEL TORRES CALVO**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Costa Rica

#### PHONE

8587-2400

#### EMAIL

daniel.torres96@hotmail.com

#### DATE OF BIRTH

27/04/1996

### **DRIVING LICENSE**

B1

### LINKS

**LinkedIn** 

<u>Portfolio</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

## SKILLS

Teamwork

Communication

Adaptability

Proactive

Troubleshooting

# LANGUAGES

Spanish

• • • •

English B2

• • • • 0

# HOBBIES

Movies

Beach

Read

Music

Travel

# PROFILE

Responsible and motivated software developer with 3+ years of experience. With knowledge about user interfaces, testing, and debugging processes. Proficient in an assortment of technologies including Java, JavaScript and excellent experience of relational databases. Able to work productively in a team in agile environments.

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Software Developer, Accenture

Heredia

Aug 2021 — Present

Back-end development with Java Spring and technologies such as Spring Boot, Maven, AEM, JPA, GraphQL, JUnit, Mockito, Jenkins, etc. Creation of new endpoints, services and resolution of problems that affect the existing integration. Develop OSGi service components to integrate with backend systems usign RESTful APIs. Work on several projects providing solutions that follows best practices with coding standards, unit testing and continuous integration.

### Software Developer, SysCo Consultores de Sistemas

San José

Nov 2019 — Aug 2021

Full-stack development with Java Spring and other technologies like Spring Boot, Maven, Spring Data, JSP, JavaScript, SASS and Oracle database. Gained experience building customer facing web based applications, web services RESTful and code collaboration in teams using GIT and SVN. Able to implement solutions to new and existing projects according to the product owner's needs.

### EDUCATION

Licentiate's degree, Computer Engineering, Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica

Feb 2021 — Present

Bachelor's degree, Systems Engineering, Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica

Feb 2019 — Nov 2019

Diploma's degree, Computer Programming, Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica

Feb 2014 — Nov 2018